## DANIEL MIDDLETON

Portfolio Site

Githul

Linkedin

https://danielmiddletono5.qithub.io/portfolio\_site/ 285 Big Pine Rd. Winchester, Ohio, USA 45697 https://github.com/danielmiddleton05 +82.010.7346.2806 daniel.middleton05@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-middleton-ab243598/ 451 Yeongtong-Ro Suwon, Gyeonggi, South Korea 16706

## **SKILLS**

LANGUAGES - Python, JavaScript, CSS, SASS, HTML, Swift

DEV TOOLS - VS Code, Visual Studio, Android Studio, Insomnia, Chrome DevTools, Lighthouse, IDLE, iOS SDK, Xcode BACK-END/CLOUD - SQL, PostgreSQL, Relational Data Modeling, Google Cloud/Firebase, Amazon Web Services FRAMEWORKS/DEV-OPS - React/React-Native, Flask, Bootstrap, Angular, Git, Docker, Continuous Integration

## **PROJECTS**

Portfolio - Created and designed using HTML, CSS, JS. Implemented JS and CSS libraries using Bootstrap and open-source projects.

Comment Generator - Using Javascript I created an auto-comment app for teachers. Stylized using Bootstrap.

International School Site - Worked with Finalsite to build an updated school website. Created pages using CSS and their CMS.

React Web App - A fake site created to showcase skills using React.js and deployed using Google Cloud/Firebase.

React-Native Mobile App - Turned the fake campground site into a React-Native app using Javascript.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# PUBLICATIONS AND TOK TEACHER/ HEAD OF DEPARTMENT | Gyeonggi Suwon International School JULY 2019 - JUNE 2023. SUWON. REPUBLIC OF KOREA

Successfully created and implemented a new curriculum in the Theory of Knowledge subject. Redesigned the Publications curriculum to promote efficiency with yearbook production; taught Adobe products and intro web design.

#### WEBSITE ADMIN AND DESIGN | Gyeonggi Suwon International School

DECEMBER 2019 - AUGUST 2022, SUWON, REPUBLIC OF KOREA

Worked with Finalsite to customize the CSS for an <u>international school website</u> and built the child pages. Also maintained content and assets.

#### **DESIGN CONSULTANT AND PHOTOGRAPHER** | Self-Employed Freelance/Contractor

AUGUST 2017 - JUNE 2020, KNOXVILLE, TN, USA

Worked in commercial photography, including real estate and products; however, I also do work in portraits, sports, concerts, and various events. Additionally, consulted in web design (front-end) and marketing for small businesses.

#### **SCIENCE TEACHER** | International School of Qingdao

AUGUST 2013 - JUNE 2017, QINGDAO, CHINA

On top of normal teaching responsibilities, oversaw the successful implementation of a new, streamlined curriculum in the middle school science department.

## **EDUCATION**

### Nucamp Coding Bootcamp | Full Stack Web Development

AUGUST 2022 - JUNE 2023, ONLINE

Worked with a small cohort of student to learn MERN Full Stack web development, primary languages include JS and Python

#### Moreland University | M.Ed. with a focus on Globalization

AUGUST 2020 - AUGUST 2021, ONLINE

A masters degree with a focus on globalization/ cross-cultural communication and how this is affecting international schools.

#### **University of Tennessee** | B.A. Chemistry

AUGUST 2017 - JUNE 2019, KNOXVILLE, TN, USA

Post graduate studies in chemistry.

#### **Johnson University** | B.S. Communications

AUGUST 2005 - MAY 2012, KNOXVILLE, TN

Half way through my education, I joined the US Marine Corp and finished my education after I was honorably discharged.